Okay, now I'm going
to show you how
to plan a roast.
What is a roast
though, Ed? Do tell.
Well, a roast is
basically where you critique
or you fix your
viewers' problems in a
video. Now, if you
don't have many viewers
because you're small, you
can do it by
fixing brands' problems or
influencers' problems or celebrities'
problems in a way
they didn't ask for.
So just use them
as an example. So
you can see this
video here. I basically
took some viewers and
I looked at their
funnel and I pointed
out why they're not
getting results and I
fixed it. So I'd
hear similar sort of
thing. And the pros
to these are, my
gosh, these will set
you apart to everyone
because most people just
repurpose blog posts. There's
not that many bona
fide experts on YouTube
and the ones that
are dominate. So if
you can just show
your expertise by literally
fixing the problem your
viewers have, it's undeniable
proof of credibility. It's
also pretty easy to
make. If you're an
expert at what you
do, you probably give
a lot of credit
to the people who
are all the time
on people's work. So
you just basically record
yourself doing that. It's
also great because we
can get a lot
of market research from
this in the way
that I show you
how to make it.
Very, very high dollar
per view. Some of
my roasts have done
$3 per view, which
just means once you
get that data, you
are pushing videos back
to that bad boy.
Very good at generating
emails, builds a lot
of community. Cons, requires
a community to get
submissions. If you're brand
new, it's not going
to be easy. However,
you can roast other
people too. Who should
make these? Any crit.
Really? So long as
you have something you
can roast. Anyone who
can visually fix or
improve something they can
show on screen. Niche
experts, musicians, designers, marketers,
craft people. And then
basically, if you're an
expert with a lot
of credibility. If you're
not, this is an
awful video to make
because your information is
going to be crap
and everyone's going to
go, you're a phony.
You're a big, dirty
phony. All right. So
who loves watching these?
Curious lurkers. People who
love seeing expert feedback
so they can go,
oh, that's my problem
too. Viewers who are
stuck with the problem.
The exact person you
are roasting has too.
Buyers sitting on the
fence. These get people
over the line because
they go, oh, I
want them to do
that for me so
bad. Here's my credit
card. They're best used
to warm up your
audience by showing you
really know your stuff.
To grow your email
list. I'll show you
why in a minute.
To convert viewers to
buyers. And the secret
sauce is keep this
as like an entertaining
tone. Keep it authentic
to yourself, but don't
be afraid to be
frank because your viewers
are going to be
watching this and they're
going to be thinking
nasty things. And if
you're not, then you're
going to be watching
this. So we don't
need to be nasty,
but think of Gordon
Ramsay and what he
does. That, if he's
a 10 out of
10 for frankness, let's
knock it down to
like a seven. The
secret sauce is also
showing the visual transformation.
So there's two types
of roasts. There's people
who come in and
go, yeah, your problem
is you're not playing
the chord G right.
Yeah. Think about our
emotion brick, showing visual
transformation, showing the problem
and then fixing it.
Right. So what I
do, and this is
what works is I
say, here's your problem.
Look, I fixed it
for you. So the
viewers can actually see,
oh my gosh, that's
what it looks like
when it's fixed. And
they connect all the
dots themselves. You also
want to pick the
most universal problems. So
if you get hundreds
of submissions and they're
all about really obscure,
weird things, don't roast
them. Just pick the
ones that relate to
most of your viewers.
Otherwise they're going to
be turned off and
then pick a max
of three things to
review per person. Every
time I've done this,
I've had like five
sheets of stuff on
one person. I'm like,
this is bad. This
is bad. And I
go, oh my gosh,
this is bad. And
then I've got to
pick the ones that
are like, what are
you doing here? Do
you know that this
is too overwhelming? Just
pick three things per
person max and move
on. So the mistakes
was a lot, not
giving clear takeaways, being
too nice or too
mean. Don't be a
dick. Failing to show
the solution. It's like
I said, pointing out
the problem is one
thing. Showing the solution
is where the results
are. Reviewing too many
pain points and not
making your information feel
new, easy or inspiring.
So the strategy we
have here is this.
We have our intro.
Then we show the
problem that viewer has.
And then that is
basically the end of
the video. And then
we show the problem
that viewer has. And
then that is basically
the emotion brick. And
then we show the
solution, which is kind
of also the emotion
brick because it's a
visual demo. But we
give some actionable insights
in this part to
give them some things
to take away. And
then we transition into
the next one and
then the next one.
And if you can
do 10 reviews, that's
fine. I usually do
three and then we
end. So show the
problem, show the fix,
ask viewers to submit
three times. And then
what you want to
do is in the
video, remind viewers, by
the way, if you
would like a review
of your thing, check
out the link below.
Do this three times
and make sure you
never call it a
roast. OK, so when
I first did this,
I said submit to
my free channel review.
I got a thousand
people apply. I did
it again the next
time and said, get
a free roast. Twenty
people applied.
So it's a free
review, not a roast.
OK, I should probably
call it that. And
then promote that you're
going to do it
on your community wall
and your email. And
what you want to
do is you go
on your community wall
and you say, I'm
going to do this
free review. And then
you're going to do
it on your community
wall. And then you
say, I'm going to
do this free review.
It's amazing. Right. I'll
give you the exact
strategy to do it.
And then you say
in order to get
it, you need to
get my email list
by 3 p .m.
today. So you drive
people to the email
and then you email
your list the form
to actually apply because
we don't want to
let people apply. We're
not on our list
unless we don't have
an email list. Titles,
just some examples. I
studied 300 insert something.
And why this? So
I studied 300 guitar
players and this wrecks
they're playing and discovered
this. And this is
what I did. And
I'm going to do
this free review. And
then you say, I'm
going to do this
free review. And this
is what makes amazing
solos like just fill
in the blanks or
you can take a
mistakes approach, which is
like five mistakes guitarists
make and how to
fix them, which doesn't
sound like a roast,
but you can say
in the intro, but
you can make it
work still. Or you
can just go roasting
my viewers X, which
can work if you
have a big community.
Thumbnails stick to results,
basically showing the result,
stick to cognitive dissonance,
basically challenging what they
thought to be true.
So saying something like
don't buy a house,
use a comparison before
and after or curiosity,
which makes them go
how, what or why.
Intro, we have a
hook. We set up
the problem or result.
We unpack the value.
We provide proof of
credibility. We match the
viewer's expectations. And then
in the emotion break,
I've already been over
this. We show the
problem. What I recommend
doing is what I'm
doing right now. So
I'm filming on this
camera, but I'm also
screen recording on this
computer, a lube. That's
why you can see
my mouse here. And
what that means is
we can have two
files. We then line
up in the edit
together, which makes the
edit easier. And if
you're using lube,
you can actually do
things like edit the
mistakes and point at
the mistakes on the
screenshots, which will actually
save your editor quite
a lot of time
too. Or you can
do what I do
a lot of the
time where I basically
do all the work
or the review and
then I write up
a script and then
I film the script
where I'm faking like
I'm giving the review.
So I'm literally presenting
your script on camera
and it looks like
I'm on my laptop.
And then afterwards I
put in the screenshots.
Most of my roasts
have done like that
because the first one
took me so long
doing it the other
way. I know, disappointing
eh? And then the
logic. Brick, brick, you
just sew the solution
steps. You show the
fixes, the three things
you did to fix
the problem. Keep screen
sharing and make sure
if you've got a
lot of information on
your screen share, you're
pointing at the thing
you want them to
look at all the
time. Your end screen,
if you're optimizing for
views, push it to
the previous version of
the video in the
series or the template,
if it was good.
Otherwise, push it to
the next logical video.
If you're optimizing for
sales, push it to
a high converting sales
video. If you're optimizing
for emails, push it
to a high converting
video for emails. So
let's have a quick
look at an intro
for one of these
roasts. And it was
called, I studied a
thousand YouTubers. This stops
them making money. And
in the thumbnail, it
said, fix your intros.
Okay, so same as
before, reds hook, orange
problem result, setups, green
transitions, blue. And it
goes like this. Are
the first 15 seconds
of your video stopping
you from making money?
That is a question
hook. Recently, thousands of
creators applied to be
roasted by me on
this channel. And most
of them are making
mistakes that wreck trust
instantly with their viewers.
And that will kill
watch time, link clicks
and sales. That's the
first one. That's the
problem result. And because
my viewers top three
problems are getting views,
sales and leads, I'd
say that's the problem.
So today I'm going
to roast three creators
and show you how
to fix their intro
problems that you probably
have too, using some
tricks that have generated
me millions. That's the
setup of value. I've
then said, here's my
credibility line. And then
we say, so this
is Patrick. Patrick emailed
to say he was
struggling to get consistent
sales. So let me
just introduce the person
and the problem they
wrote in with. The
twist is always, they
write in with a
problem that isn't the
problem they have. But
that's it. Nice, short
and simple. It matches
the expectations of the
viewers because I show
in the video the
thousands of people that
applied on my form.
And we're off. This
video did very well.
All right, so when
you're producing these, I've
already mentioned, screen record
and film yourself at
the same time or
fake the live process.
Then trim any waffle
or tangents in the
edit. Keep it concise
and keep the edit
very simple too. And
now let's look at
our planning template. So
roasts. We've got some
examples of mine here.
Just keep in mind,
they might not all
follow this exact process.
Something I've been refining
over time. Step one,
you need to ask
for submissions. So if
you have a small
audience, you can't really
get that many. So
just review famous people
or brands. And I've
written you a little
template. So put this
on your community wall.
Say, want to insert
a result they want.
I'm going to do
some free something reviews.
Don't say roasts on
the channel where I'll
show you how to
fix, insert something problem.
All you need to
do to submit, your
something for review is
sign up to my
email list below. I'll
be emailing a private
submission form to everyone
on the list in
24 hours. Keep it
simple. And then just
let them know that
they're going for you
to give feedback on
the channel. Name. I
put niche. I don't
know. It's going to
depend on your own
situation. You basically just
need to keep this
as short as possible,
but I would focus
on this. What's your
biggest struggle right now?
We want them to
admit what they think
their problem is because
they nearly always say
their problem is the
thing. It's. Not. And
you can talk about
that. If you need
a link for them
to submit photos, if
you need them to
submit photos, you could
say, put the link
to your photos here,
but don't throw this
out of too much.
Some of you might
just need name and
then link to whatever
the thing is you're
reviewing, but I would
very much recommend having
this little tick box
and then getting them
to say what their
top problem is right
now. Cause we can
use that data to
make content around. Okay.
Then what we do
is we email that
to our list and
get them to submit.
And then we start
planning the video. So
wait a few days
and set your video
goal. Sales, emails, and
views pick whichever one
you want complete the
thumbnails and titles for
it. Now to do
this, you're probably gonna
need to go through
all of your submissions
to see what sort
of problems you're gonna
talk about. So I
usually look at the
problems then work out
the thumbnail and title
based on that and
using my pattern bank.
Then we wanna have
the top three questions.
The viewers want answers
based on that packaging.
And then when you're
reviewing the submissions, one
thing I'd recommend doing
is finding a theme.
So basically you could
pick. Three people with
exactly the same problem.
So for me, it
might be thumbnails. I'll
theme each of them
about fixing thumbnail problems.
So you theme the
video or you try
different problems. So for
me, it might be
like thumbnails, titles, scripts.
There's no right or
wrong. I would try
both options, but whatever
you do, always pick
the most universal problems.
And they're gonna relate
to the biggest amount
of your potential buyers.
And then what you
do is do a
real messy plan. So
pick the people and
then just go through
bullet point, everything you'd
fix. And then after
that, refine that messy
plan. So contestant number
one, just pick three
problems you've picked up
on and then three
solutions for them. Just
plan them. So that
might mean you need
to fix something with
graphic design. That might
mean you just have
to point out and
say, look, this is
how you would solve
it. That might mean
you play the drums
yourself to show them
how to solve it,
but just plan it
like that. Contestant number
one, here's the three
things they're doing wrong.
Here's the three solutions.
Then contestant number two,
then contestant number three.
Then for our conversion
strategy, you need to
tell viewers to sign
up to your next
review three times in
the video. First in
the first 90 seconds
is optimum. You'll get
more signups then. Don't
call it a roast.
And then if you
want, you can write
your scripts like I
do, or you can
just present that from
bullet point screen recording,
like I'm doing right
now, talking to camera.
But I did find
that writing it was
actually way better in
the end. Then upload
and track and measure.
Ask, following my system,
did you hit your
goal? Repeat the lesson.
Did you not? Ask
why and avoid. Remove
the emotion. All we
need is some data
and we're making progress.